# **JOSEPH HSU**

US Citizen• github.com/JHsu01• linkedin.com/in/josephhsu1 • 317-249-7574 josephhsu2000@gmail.com

## **ABOUT**

Security/Software engineer with several years of experience in software development, project management, and embedded systems security research. Worked as a satellite flight software engineer, ran a startup, operated a consulting firm, worked as an undergraduate security researcher – while in the pursuit of a B.S in CS at Purdue. Passionate about all things security.

# **EDUCATION**

## **PURDUE UNIVERSITY**, WEST LAFAYETTE, IN

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, May 2023

• Relevant Coursework: 0-0 Programming, Programming in C, Computer Architecture, Data Structures and Algorithms, Systems Programming, Cryptography, Operating Systems, Software Engineering, Computer Security, Information Systems

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# PURDUE RESEARCH LABS, WEST LAFAYETTE, IN

Lead Researcher, June 2023 - Present

- Lead a small team of security researchers in conducting a study involving disclosed CWE's (Common Weakness Enumeration)
- Collaborate with stakeholders, including developers, directors, and company representatives to identify potential critical vulnerabilities and bugs in CWE's which may affect services and products.
- Develop a methodology to identify critical hardware vulnerabilities and notify users of possible attacks before they happen.

# NASA/US Air Force/Purdue AAE, WEST LAFAYETTE, IN

Flight Software Engineer, August 2022 - May 2023

- Manage software design and development team to meet product security requirements, while also conducting code reviews, and meeting with project stakeholders on a regular basis
- Plan, implement and monitor progress while also conforming to organization security measures and practices
- Write and develop custom software solutions for FEMTA CUBE-SAT payload (small satellites) to be deployed in space

#### FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER. CARMEL. IN

Software Developer/ Web Dev Consultant, May 2017 - Present

- Work closely with clients to understand their needs, provide technical support, and develop custom software solutions to meet their unique requirements.
- Maintain and update existing software and website applications, ensuring compatibility with current and future operating systems and web browsers

## TEXTRON, AVILLA, IN

LDP IT Intern, May 2022 - August 2022

- Create macros and systems in excel to help keep track of product testing schedules, while also updating and writing documentation for Kautex-Textron security assets.
- Test, document, and deploy written custom SAP backup infrastructure to all Kautex-Textron locations in North America
- Write and develop custom SAP-related backup infrastructure to reduce overall downtime for manufacturing lines

# **SKILLS**

- C, Java, python, HTML, JS, CSS, React, SQL
- Jira, Confluence, APIs, AWS (Lambda, Amplify)
- Scrum Master/Project management experience
- Android Studio, Flutter
- Automation/Software Engineering
- Hackathon/Competitive Hacking (CTF)

# **SELECTED PROJECTS**

## **CUSTOM SAP BACKUP INFASTRUCTURE**

Intern project assigned at Avilla, Kautex-Textron plant. Created backup network page so that production could continue to make rack labels and track items even if Wi-Fi or SAP went down, leading to a decrease in overall downtime. Estimated to save the company **~\$60k/yr**.

#### STUDY WITH CLASS

**Placed 1st** at Purdue's Hackathon BOILERMAKE IX. Wrote the frontend and helped with SQL integration. The end product was a program that created study groups based on parsed calendar inputs- looking for common free time in all given calendars. Built with Flask, Twilio's API, & python

# **ORGINIZATIONS & LEADERSHIP**

- CARY CLUB RA Representative, September 2021 May 2023
- **SUPREME COURT OF PURDUE -** Clerk to Chief Justice, Feb 2021 May 2023
- PURDUE STUDENT GOVERNMENT Director of Technology, July 2021- May 2023
- **PURDUE FENCING -**Armorer, August 2022 May 2023

